Guide to the Beecher Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject File, 1706-1818, 1830-1948; Series IV; 3' 9" (11 boxes)
  - Tilton Scandal
    - State on Congregational Policy with reference to the Action of the Action of the Church of the Pilgrims and the Clinton Avenue Church, Brooklyn. "Read At Ministers Meeting in Massachusetts, Dec. 22, 1873 by a Congregational Pastor" (Box 87, Folder 216)
    - Protest by Clinton Avenue Congregational Church Dec 25, 1873. And related documents (Box 87, Folder 217)
    - Fragments on Tilton Scandal, 1874 (Box 87, Folder 218)
    - "Proceedings of the Plymouth Church Investigating Committee, Sixth Session", July 14, 1874 (Box 87, Folder 219)
    - Caverno, Rev. C., The Brooklyn Council Chicago, pamphlet, 1874 (Box 87, Folder 220)
    - The Veil Removed or Henry Ward Beecher Trial and Acquittal, [n.y. 1874] (Box 87, Folder 221)
    - Clippings, 1874, 1875-1876, 1907 (Box 87, Folder 222-223)
      - Oversized newspaper pages, 1875 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Circular of the Committee for a Public Reception for Henry Ward Beecher at end of Tilton Trial, 1875 (Box 87, Folder 224)
    - The Case of Henry Ward Beecher: Opening Address by Benjamin F. Tracy, [n.y. 1875] (Box 87, Folder 225)
    - "Letter Missive" (from Plymouth Church) re: Advisory Council of 1876 (Box 87, Folder 226)
    - List of proposed delegates to the advisory council of 1876 (Box 87, Folder 227)
    - Proceedings of the Advisory Council-Brooklyn 1876 (Box 87, Folder 228)
    - Resolution by the Congregational Association of New York and Brooklyn, November 1, 1876 (Box 87, Folder 229)
    - Uncontradicted Testimony in the Beecher Case, Comp. Lyman Abbott, [n.y. 1876] (Box 87, Folder 230)
    - On Henry Ward Beecher's relations with Theodore Tilton [fragment], undated (Box 87, Folder 231)
- Photographs, 1833-19-; Series V; 1' 6" (4 boxes)
  This series contains engravings, portraits, photographic plates and slides of members of the Beecher, Scoville, and Bullard Families. In addition there are photographs, et al. taken or collected by family members. Photos of an individual are filed under the person's name, followed by photos (if any) of people, places or events in that person's life. Not included in this series are photographs pertaining to Hampton Institute or to Indians. These are to be found in the SUBJECT FILE (Series IV).
  - Beecher Family
    - Cartes de visite of Public Figures, Agassiz-Stephens (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Cartes de visite of various children (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Cartes de visites of various men (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Cartes de visite of various women (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Col. E.E. Ellsworth, engraving (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Col. Henry Barton Beecher (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Beecher, Herbert Foote and Beecher, William Constantine, [c.1859] (Box 88, Folder 7)
      See: Folio 99
      - Oversize photograph, Circa 1859 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Foote, George A. (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Olympic Mountains, La Roshe, 1891 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Oversize photograph, 1891 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Dame Ellen Terry (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Foote, Roxanna Ward, Silhouette (Box 88, Folder 10a)
  - Beecher, Edward
    - Beecher, Edward in middle and old age (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Beecher, Eunice White (Bullard)
    - As a young woman (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - In old age (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - In old age, portraits (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - In old age (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - With family and friends at resort (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - With Aunt Hattie Stowe and children on goat cart, undated (Folder 100)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward
    - As a young man, daguerreotype (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Copy of 1846 portrait (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - As a young man (Box 88, Folder 19)
      - Oversized photographs (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Approximately age 40-50, eleven portraits (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - In middle and old age (Box 88, Folder 21)
      - Oversized photographs, undated (Box 99, Folder 5, Folder 100, Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous portraits (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - As a young man (Box 88, Folder 23)
      See: Folio 99 for additional photos
    - Portrait (Box 88, Folder 24-25)
    - Portraits, H. W. B. in group pictures (Box 88, Folder 26)
    - Henry Ward Beecher family portraits. (Box 88, Folder 27)
      - Oversize photographs, undated (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Henry Ward Beecher and Eunice White Beecher on Stagecoach (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - Henry Ward Beecher Funeral service in Plymouth Church (Box 88, Folder 29)
    - Plymouth Church (2 views) (Box 88, Folder 30)
    - Slave Children [one redeemed in Plymouth Church] (Box 88, Folder 31)
    - H. W. B.'s homes, stereopticon slides and ink drawing. (Box 88, Folder 32)
      See also: Folio 100
      - Oversized drawing, Undated (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - H. W. B.'s Country home., 1872 (Box 88, Folder 33)
      See also: Folio 100 for Hillside: the Summer Rest of H. W. B., photographed and published by George G. Rockwood
      - Hillside: The Summer Rest of Henry Ward Beecher, photographed and published by George G. Rockwood, 1872 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - H. W. B. and the officers of his regiment. (Box 88, Folder 34)
      - Oversized photographs, Undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - H. W. B.'s Favorite horses (Box 88, Folder 35)
  - Beecher, Lyman
    - Engraving (Box 88, Folder 36)
    - Portrait. (Box 88, Folder 37)
      See also: Box 78
    - L. Beecher family (Photograph by Matthew Brady). (Box 88, Folder 38)
      - Oversize photograph, undated (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - L. B.'s home in Cincinnati (Box 88, Folder 39)
  - Beecher, Thomas (Box 88, Folder 39a)
  - Bullard Family
    - Bullard Family. (Box 89, Folder 40)
      - Old Bullard homestead, Sutton, Mass., Undated (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Hampton Institute, Students, teachers. (Box 89, Folder 41)
      See: Box 80, Folder 66
      See also: Box 82, Folder 122
    - Indians. (Box 89, Folder 42)
  - Hooker, Isabella Beecher (Box 89, Folder 42a)
  - Scoville Family
    - Devan, Harriet (Scoville) (Box 89, Folder 43-44)
    - Devan, Scoville T. (Box 89, Folder 45)
    - Scoville, Harriet E. (Beecher)
      - Scoville, Harriet E. (Beecher) (Box 89, Folder 46-47)
      - Samuel and Harriet E.B. Scoville (Box 89, Folder 48)
      - Funeral pictures of Harry Scoville? (Box 89, Folder 49)
    - Scoville, Rev. Samuel
      - Scoville, Rev. Samuel (Box 89, Folder 50)
    - Scoville, Samuel Jr.
      - Scoville, Samuel Jr. (Box 89, Folder 51)
    - Scoville, William Herbert
      - Scoville, William Herbert (Box 89, Folder 52)
      - "Grandfather Hurlbutt" (Box 89, Folder 53)
      - Portraits, Miscellaneous (Box 89, Folder 54)
  - Scoville, Annie Beecher
    See: box 84, folder 169
    - Annie Beecher Scoville, photos. (Box 89, Folder 55)
    - Annie Beecher Scoville as a girl (Box 89, Folder 56)
    - Annie Beecher Scoville (Box 89, Folder 57)
    - Annie Beecher Scoville and Katharine Lee Bates (Box 89, Folder 58)
    - Florence Holbrook (Box 89, Folder 59)
    - Photographs of Scoville family and home (Box 89, Folder 60)
    - Negatives, miscellaneous (Box 89, Folder 61)
    - Photographic plates, charcoal burners (Box 89, Folder 62)
    - Photographic plates - Scoville family and miscellaneous (Box 89, Folder 63)
    - Art reproductions and engravings, miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 64)
    - Photographs - European views and monuments. (Box 90, Folder 65)
    - Album - European views and monuments (Box 90, Folder 66)
    - Slides - Art Reproductions (Box 91, Folder 67)
    - Slides - Military reviews (Box 91, Folder 68)
    - Photographs, miscellaneous unidentified
      - Portraits of men (Box 91, Folder 69-70)
      - Portraits of women (Box 91, Folder 71)
      - Portraits of children (Box 91, Folder 72)
      - Photographs, miscellaneous unidentified (Box 91, Folder 73-76)
  - Stowe, Harriet (Beecher)
    - Stowe, Harriet (Beecher) portraits (Box 91, Folder 77)
    - Ralph Waldo Emerson (Box 91, Folder 78)
    - Stowe, Frederick William (Box 91, Folder 79)
    - James T. Field, H.B.S.'s publisher; Annie Field, her biographer (Box 91, Folder 80)
  - Unidentified Add. 8/30/82 (Box 91, Folder 81)
- Special Files, 1795-1817, 1847-1950; Series VI; 2' 4"(6 boxes)
  The SPECIAL FILES contain the accounts, business correspondence and legal papers of Beecher-Scoville family members and their estates. Included are checks, receipts, bank statements, contracts, mortgages and records of land sales. In addition, there are drawings by family members and a section of miscellaneous materials, consisting of flyers and broadsides, old newspapers, maps, indentures, and genealogical materials.
  - Beecher, Henry Ward
    - Accounts
      - Accounts, 1847-1869, 1873-1887, undated (Box 92, Folder 1-5)
    - Estate of Henry Ward Beecher- Correspondence re:
      - Arnold - Chippewa Valley Bank (Box 92, Folder 6)
      - Bailey, C. L., 1890-1892 (Box 92, Folder 7)
      - Beecher, William Constantine (Box 92, Folder 8)
      - Cherryman, William, 1890-1898, undated (Box 92, Folder 9)
      - Cole - Kempton (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - Estate of Luther Beecher, 1892-1895 (Box 92, Folder 11)
      - McBain, Gillis, 1890-1895 (Box 92, Folder 12)
      - McKesson - Richard and Pace (Box 92, Folder 13)
      - Misaukee Co., Mich. Treasurer, 1897-1899 (Box 92, Folder 14)
      - Northrup, Elmore S., 1898-1899, undated (Box 92, Folder 15)
      - North Western Lumber Co. - U.S. (Box 92, Folder 16)
      - Rancour, A., 1898-1899 (Box 92, Folder 17)
      - Revard Bros., 1897 (Box 92, Folder 18)
      - Simons, D.P., 1894-1898 (Box 92, Folder 19)
    - Estate Documents
      - Accounts, 1887-1903 (Box 93, Folder 20)
      - Checks and receipts, 1860-1898 (Box 93, Folder 21)
      - Contracts, deeds, etc, of the village of Beecher, Benzie Co., Mich. record of 1890-1895 (Box 93, Folder 22)
      - Documents of Agreement, Indenture and other papers relating to estate., 1846, 1868-1899 (Box 93, Folder 23)
      - Land contracts, 1890-1893 (Box 93, Folder 24-25)
      - Land sales (Box 93, Folder 26)
      - Lands for Beecher, Mich. Documents and maps relating to the town (Box 93, Folder 27)
      - Receipts for purchases of William Cherryman for the estate of H.W.B., 1891-1895 (Box 93, Folder 28)
      - Report upon lands by Samuel Scoville (Box 93, Folder 29)
    - Estate of H.W.B. - catalog
      - Catalog of the Bric-a-brac, rare oriental rugs, oil paintings.. and the valuable library belonging to the estate of the late Henry Ward Beecher (Box 93, Folder 30)
      - List of articles bought by Harriet E.B. Scoville at auction of H.W.B. estate (Box 93, Folder 31)
    - Books and certificates from the H.W.B. estate
      - Bible presented to Eunice Beecher by Lyman Beecher (Box 94, Folder 32)
      - Copy of Baxter's Saints' Rest presented to Eunice White Bullard by Henry Ward Beecher (Box 94, Folder 33)
      - Kansas State Historical Society, Diploma of membership., 1879 May 26 January 20 1885 (Box 94, Folder 33a)
      - New England Historic-Genealogical Society, certificate of membership., August 3 1859 (Box 94, Folder 33b)
  - Scoville Family
    - Scoville Accounts - Harriet B. and Samuel B. Scoville
      - Expense Accounts, 1890-1893 (Box 94, Folder 34)
      - Expenses of our ranch, 1900 (Box 94, Folder 35)
      - Receipts, 1859-1948, 1850-1912, undated, 1859-1948 (Box 94, Folder 36-38)
      - Travel Permit of Spanish Consulate H.B. Scoville, Apr, 1871 (Box 94, Folder 39)
    - Samuel B. Scoville and Harriet B. Scoville Estates
      - Samuel B. Scoville estate, Account of Executors, Will of S.B. Scoville, 1912 (Box 94, Folder 40)
      - Harriet B. Scoville Estate, Accounts of Interest, of executors and agreements, 1860,1899-1917 (Box 94, Folder 41)
      - S.B. Scoville, Article of Indenture - H.W.B.-S.B.S.; Crops Grown, 1886 Statement, 1898-1899 (Box 94, Folder 42)
      - Scoville, William Herbert, "List of House Furniture, 1942 (Box 94, Folder 43)
  - Scoville, Annie Beecher
    - Accounts
      - Receipts, 1885-1916 (Box 95, Folder 44)
      - Policies, Insurance Co. and mortgage, 1893-1950 (Box 95, Folder 45)
      - Bills, Loans, Receipts (incl. National Indian Association), 1900-1934 (Box 95, Folder 46)
      - Receipts, 1917-1949, undated (Box 95, Folder 47)
    - Checks
      - Checks, 1863-1887, 1890-1948 (Box 95, Folder 48-51)
      - Checkbook and stubs, 1909-1942 (Box 95, Folder 52)
  - Drawings
    - Floral painting presented to Annie Beecher Scoville by Harriet Beecher Stowe. (Box 96, Folder 53)
    - Ink drawing - Annie Beecher Scoville (Box 96, Folder 54)
    - Ink wash drawing - "Jacobs Und Josephs Zusammenkunft" (artist unknown) (Box 96, Folder 55)
    - Sketchbook, Annie Beecher Scoville (Box 96, Folder 56-59)
  - Miscellaneous
    - The Amethyst, History and Description of (Box 96, Folder 60)
    - Book of Addresses and contributions, Ct., 1871-1920? (Box 96, Folder 61)
    - Calling Cards (Box 96, Folder 62)
    - Christian Union; 10th Anniversary Statement by editor, (c. 1880 Jan) (Box 96, Folder 63)
    - Clubs and Societies (Annie Beecher Scoville) (Box 96, Folder 64)
    - Connecticut Forestry Association (Box 96, Folder 65)
    - Copper plates bearing H.W.B. 's name (Box 96, Folder 66)
    - Wm. T. Elliott and Co. - Offer of a prize in the Royal Havana or Cuba plan lottery, undated (Box 96, Folder 67)
    - Flyers and Broadsides (Box 96, Folder 68)
    - Genealogy: Beecher (Box 96, Folder 69)
    - Genealogies: Brown, Hooker, Langdon, Lewis, Meigs, Porter, Smith, White, Wilcox, Willard (Box 96, Folder 70)
    - Greeting Cards and Post Cards, misc. (Box 96, Folder 71)
    - Hughes, Charles T., Estate of Legal Documents (Box 97, Folder 72)
    - Indenture, Franklin Wesley - James Sachet (Box 97, Folder 72a)
    - Invitations, misc. (Box 97, Folder 73)
    - Maps, plans, and charts, misc. (Box 97, Folder 74)
      See also: Folio 99
      - Chart representing U.S. political parties, Washington-cleveland administrations, 1895 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Maps, volume compiled by Edward Beecher (Box 97, Folder 74a)
    - Old newspapers, etc., 1795-1817 (Box 97, Folder 75)
    - Pamphlets, misc. (probably Annie Beecher Scoville) (Box 97, Folder 76)
    - Pamphlets, misc. (probably A. B. S.) (Box 97, Folder 77)
    - Pamphlets, Misc. [probably T. K. B.], undated (Box 97, Folder 77a)
    - Postcard - Edward Beecher's first church (Box 97, Folder 78)
    - Postcard - Houses of H. B. S. (Box 97, Folder 79)
    - Postcards - Natick, Mass. Birthplace of Calvin Ellis Stowe (Box 97, Folder 80)
    - Postcards - West Cornwall, Conn., Ancestral home of the Scoville Family (Box 97, Folder 81)
    - Yale Alumni Association of Fairfield Country (Conn.) and vicinity, 1887 (Box 97, Folder 82)
    - Memorabilia Add. 8/30/82 (Box 97, Folder 83)
    - Handkerchieves, Silk scarf Add. 8/30/82 (Box 97, Folder 84)
    - Folio 1 (Box 98)
- Additional Material, 1868-1930; Accession 2011-M-073
  - Correspondence
    - Bacon, George, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Written by Theodore D. Bacon to Rev. George Bacon. Orginial and copy printed in 1930.
    - Beecher, Henry (Mr. and Mrs.), 1868 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beecher, William and Louise, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      20 letters and 1 Christmas greeting.
    - Scoville, William H., 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, Circa 1931-1945; Accession 19ND-M-016
  This accession consists of twenty-four 16mm films of or by William Herbert Scoville, as well as a handwritten film log and editing notes. The film log identifies each film by a sequential number from 1 to 68 and includes notes regarding the contents and technical details of each film. The editing notes seem to indicate both edits that were made to some of the films, as well as suggestions for editing. Not all of the films documented in the log and editing notes are included in the accession.
  Ten of the films in the accession were identified on their original canisters with an identifying number that presumably corresponds to the same number recorded in the log and editing notes. Eight of the films were identified on their original canisters with a brief description, and six were completely unidentified.
  - Film log, Circa 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Film editing notes, Circa 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 16 mm films
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Reel #1, Circa 1931 (Box 2)
    - Reel #2, Circa 1931 (Box 3)
    - Reel #3, Circa 1931 (Box 4A)
    - Reel #4, Circa 1931 (Box 4)
    - Reel #6, Circa 1931 (Box 5)
    - Reel #7, Circa 1931 (Box 6)
    - Reel #9, Circa 1931 (Box 7)
    - Reel #10, Circa 1931 (Box 8)
    - Reel #11, Circa 1931 (Box 9)
    - Reel #12, Circa 1931 (Box 10)
    - Reel #13, Circa 1931 (Box 11)
    - Reel #26, 28, 29-32 (duplicate), Circa 1931 (Box 11A)
    - Abschum ("Evacuation"), Circa 1939-1945 (Box 12)
    - Action footage: Nazi planes gunning U.S. planes, Circa 1939-1945 (Box 13)
    - Bazaars of Cairo; Egypt; Memphis; Java, Circa 1931 (Box 14)
    - Canton; Hong Kong; Peking; Shanghai; Formosa, Circa 1931 (Box 15)
    - Columbo; Rangoon; Singapore; Bangkok; Ceylon; Benares, Circa 1931 (Box 16)
    - Falls animals, Circa 1931 (Box 17)
    - India, Circa 1931 (Box 18)
    - Japan: Mjajama, Kobe, Nikko, Nara, Kyoto; Rainbow Falls, Hilo, Circa 1931 (Box 18A)
    - New York; Algiers; Jerusalem; Macassar; Madeira; Zamboanga, Circa 1931 (Box 19)
    - Unidentified films, Circa 1931 (Box 20–24)
    - Zanzibar, Circa 1931 (Box 25)
- Additional material, 1875; Accession 2017-M-0004
  This accession comprises an autograph book signed by participants in the trial of Tilton v. Beecher, in which Henry Ward Beecher was accused of committing adultery with Theodore Tilton's wife. Signatures include Beecher's, the jury members, and the plantiff's and defendant's counsel.
  - Autograph book, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 1)